<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2 | Haziq Jamil</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication-type/2/</link><atom:link href="https://haziqj.ml/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>2</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2023 Haziq Jamil</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haziqj.ml/media/icon_hu4b886e67ce091368601699b05489f639_45390_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>2</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication-type/2/</link></image><item><title>Extremal hyper-Zagreb index of trees of given segments with applications to regression modeling in QSPR studies</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/hayat-2023-extremal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/hayat-2023-extremal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Statistical significance of valency-based topological descriptors for correlating thermodynamic properties of benzenoid hydrocarbons with applications</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/hayat-2023-statistical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/hayat-2023-statistical/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The domination number of the king's graph</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/arshad-2023-domination/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/arshad-2023-domination/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Factors Affecting Readmission to a Drug Rehabilitation Centre in Brunei Darussalam</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/jali-2022-factors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/jali-2022-factors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Iron and Manganese Mobilisation due to Dam Height Increase for a Tropical Reservoir in South East Asia</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/godeke-2022-increase/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/godeke-2022-increase/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pairwise likelihood estimation for confirmatory factor analysis models with categorical variables and data that are missing at random</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/katsikatsou-pairwise-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/katsikatsou-pairwise-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Latent Class Analysis: Insights about design and analysis of schistosomiasis diagnostic studies</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/koukounari-latent-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/koukounari-latent-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="author-summary">Author Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Accurate schistosomiasis diagnosis is essential to assess the impact of large scale and repeated mass drug administration to control or even eliminate this disease.
However, in schistosomiasis diagnostic studies, several inherent study design issues pose a real challenge for the currently available statistical tools used for diagnostic modelling and associated data analysis and conclusions.
More specifically, those study design issues are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>the inclusion of small number of diagnostic tests (i.e. most often five),&lt;/li>
&lt;li>non formal consensus about a schistosomiasis gold standard,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the contemporary use of relatively small sample sizes in relevant studies due to lack of research funding,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the differing levels of prevalence of the studied disease even within the same area of one endemic country and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>other real world factors such as: the lack of appropriate equipment, the variability of certain methods due to biological phenomena and training of technicians across the endemic countries because of scarce financial resources contributing to the existing lack of a schistosomiasis gold standard.
The current study aims to caution practitioners from blindly applying statistical models with small number of diagnostic tests and sample sizes, proposing design guidelines of future schistosomiasis diagnostic accuracy studies with recommendations for further research.
While our study is centred around the diagnosis of schistosomiasis, we feel that the recommendations can be adapted to other major tropical infectious diseases as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Investigating the effect of load carriage on soldiers' performances using Bayesian structural equation models</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/publication/jamil-2020-investigating/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/publication/jamil-2020-investigating/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>