<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Future-projects | Haziq Jamil</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/</link><atom:link href="https://haziqj.ml/future-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Future-projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2023 Haziq Jamil</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haziqj.ml/media/icon_hu4b886e67ce091368601699b05489f639_45390_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Future-projects</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/</link></image><item><title>Efficient methods for truncated normal distributions</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/truncated-normal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/truncated-normal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Truncated normal distributions often appear in the estimation of various important statistical models, for example, binary and multinomial probit models, tobit models, and constrained linear regresion.
Often times, a substantial part of the estimation algorithm involves the computation of moments or probabilities of the truncated normal distribution.
It is therefore important that the computational backend for producing these values of interest is made as efficient as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among other things, it would be interesting to look at the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Efficient ways to obtain moments $\text{E}[g(X)]$ where $X$ is distributed according to a truncated normal distribution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Efficient ways to obtain probabilities involving truncated normal distributions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Univariate and multivariate truncated normal distributions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The main goal for this project is to create an &lt;code>R&lt;/code> package which can be used by other developers and researchers for their specific usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work involved: literature review and survey of current methods, identifying bottlenecks in algorithms, propose methodology to overcome such bottlenecks, software design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scoring individual abilities using multilevel latent variable models</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/latent-physical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/latent-physical/</guid><description>&lt;p>Often, key constructs of interest remain elusive in a quantitative study because they are impossible to measure directly.
Examples from social science studies include individuals&amp;rsquo; intelligence quotient (IQ), or political tendencies (left or right).
However, under a reflective measurement theory, we can propose that these constructs influence the outcome of several tests which can be measured directly (e.g., IQ can be measured by appropriate IQ tests, and political tendencies by appropriate survey questions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taking this cue from the social sciences, it would be interesting to see this type of methodology being applied to sports and fitness.
Spefically, this study comes from a performance optimisation standpoint.
Under what conditions do athletes perform best?
Athletes&amp;rsquo; performance can be considered to be latent in nature, but several test items can be constructed to measure the latent variable indirectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It would also be interesting to construct a non-parametric relationship between several explanatory variables and the latent variable of interest in the structural part of the model.
Doing so would allow for better flexibility and predictive abilities.
One idea would be to include a Gaussian process regression (GPR) in the structural equation model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project can be applied in nature, but there is also substantive scope to look into methodology.
For instance, a writeup of the estimation of such models when there is a GPR would certainly be noteworthy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spatio-temporal analysis of Brunei data</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/spatio-temporal-brunei/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/spatio-temporal-brunei/</guid><description>&lt;p>For my PhD project, I modelled the probabilities of farm houses contracting a particular type of bovine tuberculosis (BTB) over time in Cornwall, UK.
I thought something similar could be done specifically for Bruneian data, but not necessarily BTB data of course.
Some ideas include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Economic data (income, unemployment, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Educattional data (student-teach ratio, percentage passes in exams, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demographic data (fertility rate, mortality rate, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Business data (number of coffee shops, land prices, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The challenge here firstly would be first to acquire data for analysis, which is not readily available.
There are official sources for some of these data, but for unstructured data which may be scattered all over the internet and social media, it would be interesting to come up with a device that can scrape these types of data automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Secondly, at a minimum, this project involves visualisation of the data set.
Since these are also temporal data (over time), animations play a vital role here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirdly, appropriate models are to be constructed for prediction of future time values or spatial points for which we have no data on.
I would propose looking at some machine learning techniques for this part.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>