<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Future-projects | Haziq Jamil</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/</link><atom:link href="https://haziqj.ml/future-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Future-projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2023 Haziq Jamil</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://haziqj.ml/media/icon_hu4b886e67ce091368601699b05489f639_45390_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Future-projects</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/</link></image><item><title>Statistical modelling of spatio-temporal data: An application to property prices in Brunei</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/spatial-brunei/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/spatial-brunei/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This project involves the use of quantitative methods and data analysis techniques to examine the relationships between various factors that affect the price of real estate. The importance of property prices as a macroeconomic indicator for a country cannot be overstated, as it has significant implications for the overall health of the economy. Property prices are not only an essential component of household wealth but also influence the spending patterns of consumers, the lending policies of financial institutions, and the investment decisions of businesses. Thus, understanding the dynamics of property prices through statistical modeling is crucial for policymakers, investors, and other stakeholders to make informed decisions that can affect the direction of the economy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="research-objectives">Research objectives&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To conduct an overarching literature review of data analytic techniques and statistical models used in spatio-temporal analyses across various disciplines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To build a statistical model suitable for both explaining and predicting property prices in Brunei, and offer sociological and economic explanations for the observed phenomena.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To analyse trends of house ownership from an affordability standpoint based on market price data available on alternative sources (e.g. social media), and compare its reliability with oﬀicial statistics. [c.f. &lt;a href="https://www.bdcb.gov.bn/Lists/News/DisplayItem.aspx?ID=430&amp;amp;ContentTypeId=0x01040013E26435B72C28499D11105B93AD3652" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RPPI&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="knowledge-areas">Knowledge areas&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Statistical modelling: Generalised linear models, Generalised additive models (GAMs), Gaussian process regression, Spatial autoregressive models.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Model estimation: EM algorithms, MCMC methods, INLA technique, Variational inference.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Economics: Hedonic regression, RPPI as a macroeconomic indicator.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Data analytics: Visualisation of spatial data (GIS and shape file), Automated data scraping.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="projects">Projects&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Analysis of factors affecting residential property prices in Brunei&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Building the RPPI using alternative sources: A comparative study in Brunei&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Exploring factors affecting rental property prices in Brunei&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Collating socio-demographic spatio-temporal data in Brunei for modelling purposes&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="members">Members&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Haziq Jamil [PI]. &lt;em>Assistant Professor in Statistics&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lutfi Abdul Razak. &lt;em>Lecturer in Economics&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Indira Puteri Kinasih. &lt;em>PhD Mathematics candidate&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dk Nur Amira Barizah @ Dk Nur Aisyah Pg Noorosmawie. &lt;em>BSc Mathematics candidate&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Nur Husnina Muhammad Zuhairi. &lt;em>BSc Mathematics candidate&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Atikah Farhain Yahya. &lt;em>BSc Mathematics candidate&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Efficient methods for truncated normal distributions</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/truncated-normal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/truncated-normal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Truncated normal distributions often appear in the estimation of various important statistical models, for example, binary and multinomial probit models, tobit models, and constrained linear regresion.
Often times, a substantial part of the estimation algorithm involves the computation of moments or probabilities of the truncated normal distribution.
It is therefore important that the computational backend for producing these values of interest is made as efficient as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among other things, it would be interesting to look at the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Efficient ways to obtain moments $\text{E}[g(X)]$ where $X$ is distributed according to a truncated normal distribution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Efficient ways to obtain probabilities involving truncated normal distributions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Univariate and multivariate truncated normal distributions.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The main goal for this project is to create an &lt;code>R&lt;/code> package which can be used by other developers and researchers for their specific usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work involved: literature review and survey of current methods, identifying bottlenecks in algorithms, propose methodology to overcome such bottlenecks, software design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scoring individual abilities using multilevel latent variable models</title><link>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/latent-physical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haziqj.ml/future-project/latent-physical/</guid><description>&lt;p>Often, key constructs of interest remain elusive in a quantitative study because they are impossible to measure directly.
Examples from social science studies include individuals&amp;rsquo; intelligence quotient (IQ), or political tendencies (left or right).
However, under a reflective measurement theory, we can propose that these constructs influence the outcome of several tests which can be measured directly (e.g., IQ can be measured by appropriate IQ tests, and political tendencies by appropriate survey questions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taking this cue from the social sciences, it would be interesting to see this type of methodology being applied to sports and fitness.
Spefically, this study comes from a performance optimisation standpoint.
Under what conditions do athletes perform best?
Athletes&amp;rsquo; performance can be considered to be latent in nature, but several test items can be constructed to measure the latent variable indirectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It would also be interesting to construct a non-parametric relationship between several explanatory variables and the latent variable of interest in the structural part of the model.
Doing so would allow for better flexibility and predictive abilities.
One idea would be to include a Gaussian process regression (GPR) in the structural equation model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project can be applied in nature, but there is also substantive scope to look into methodology.
For instance, a writeup of the estimation of such models when there is a GPR would certainly be noteworthy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>